Don Alonzo Sanford Papers 1812-1983 1870-1915
University of Arizona Library Special Collections
Don Alonzo Sanford Papers Collection 1812-1983 1870-1915
MS 451
Sanford, Don Alonzo
Papers, 1812-1983 (bulk 1870-1915). This collection contains materials relating to Don Alonzo Sanford, a prominent resident of Territorial Arizona who was a Patagonia cattle/ sheep rancher and Tucson politician, as well as a successful Washington, D.C. businessman. This collection is comprised of correspondence, documents, deeds, diaries/ledgers and photographs. The bulk of the material relates to Sanford’s Arizona ranch as well as his varied business interests in both Tucson and Washington, D.C. The collection also contains legal records relating to the San Jose de Sonoita land grant. Also included are various maps, blueprints, postcards and negatives.
30 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
None
Empire Ranch Records, 1874-1944 (AZ 246)
Papers of Richard Summers, 1925-1962 (AZ 560)
Dark Madonna, ca. 1936-1937. By Richard Summers(AZ 180)
Richard A. Summers: a bio-bibliography and literary checklist, 1973(AZ 346)
Biographical Note
Born on January 28, 1840 in Honeoye Falls, New York, Don Alonzo Sanford spent his early years working in various areas such as painting, carriage making, dentistry and law enforcement (as deputy sheriff) before deciding to move to the West to make his fortune. In about 1870 he joined his brother Denton Sanford in Texas (who had been bringing supplies in from California and driving cattle since 1862) to engage in driving cattle. During a large cattle drive from Texas to California with his brother Denton in 1872, Kiowa and Comanche warriors attacked their party and stole their livestock and horses. This put an end to Don A. Sanford’s days of driving cattle. In 1873 he traveled to Washington, D.C. to file a claim for redress by the U.S. government of the damages suffered as part of this “Indian Depredation”. While in Washington, D.C., he met Louisa Jane Bloxton, a young woman originally from Pennsylvania. After returning to Arizona, the two corresponded for two years while he was establishing a cattle ranch called the Stock Valley Ranch near Sonoita. In 1875, Louisa Bloxton and her brother Benjamin traveled from Washington, D.C. to Tucson. After arriving, Louisa Bloxton placed a claim on additional ranch land in the Sonoita Valley where she lived until she married Don Sanford on October 5, 1875 in Tucson. Sanford raised barley and beef which he sold to army outposts at Camp Crittenden and Camp Huachuca. Eventually Sanford sold his ranch to Walter Vail of the Empire Ranch and the Sanford family moved to the Patagonia ranch lands (known as the Aztec Ranch /97 Ranch) of his now deceased brother Denton. They lived on their ranch with their family which grew to include daughters Etta, Ada (who died as an infant), Amo, Mabel, and Bertha, as well as son Don, Jr.
In addition to ranching interests, Don Sanford also was involved in political matters in Tucson during the 1880s, serving as Councilman, Chairman of the Printing Committee and as acting Mayor in 1884. In addition, the Sanford’s’ purchased several properties in Tucson which they rented to various businesses and residents. After years living on their ranch in Patagonia, the family decided to move back to Washington, D.C. in about 1886. Don Sanford continued to manage ranch business from both afar and through frequent visits to Arizona. While living in Washington, D.C., he expanded his business interests to include several rental properties including the Arizona Hotel and The Patience/ The Rochester Hotel. He was an astute businessman who bought, remodeled and rented out many properties in the city. He kept meticulous records and accounts of his various business interests and recorded them in ledgers he termed the “Books of Knowledge”.
Don Sanford and his wife Louisa were also strong supporters of the Temperance Movement and assisted Carry Nation in her efforts to outlaw alcohol, including posting her bail for release from jail in 1909 and providing her with a residence in Washington, D.C. A man of varied interests, Don Alonzo Sanford also enjoyed travel, drawing and was fluent in Spanish. He died in Washington, D.C. on May 15, 1915 at the age of 75. The ranch land in Patagonia was sold by family members in 1925 to the Zinsmeister family and became known as the Circle Z Ranch.
Arrangement
This Collection is organized into 10 series.
Series I: Correspondence
Subseries 1: Business
Subseries 2: Personal
Subseries 3: Letter Books
Series II: Diaries/Ledgers
Series III: Ranch Records
Series IV: Property Records
Series V: Legal Records
Series VI: Political Records
Series VII: Financial Records
Series VIII: Family Records
Series IX: Photographs and negatives
Series X: Oversize materials
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1812-1983 (bulk 1870-1915). This collection is comprised of the correspondence, documents, diaries/ledgers and photographs of Don Alonzo Sanford. The bulk of the material relates to his many years as owner of a large cattle/sheep ranch in the Sonoita Valley near Patagonia, Arizona. These materials include correspondence, legal documents, livestock records, and other materials relating to the history, development, and operation of ranch property in Southern Arizona. Correspondence with ranchers, vaqueros and other residents of Southern Arizona/Borderlands region during the 1870’s-1890’s shed light on the Territorial Arizona life. Documents detailing Sanford’s time driving cattle in 1860’s Texas, and later cattle and sheep ranching in Arizona, with his brother Denton Sanford are also present. Their claims of redress from the U.S. Government for losses suffered by the Sanford brothers when their cattle were stolen by Kiowa and Comanche warriors can be found in the “Indian Depredations” materials. The collection also includes materials concerning the San Jose de Sonoita land grant and the Baca Float, including the Sanford vs. Ainsa case argued before the U.S. Supreme Court in 1912. Financial and property records also relate to Sanford’s extensive business interests as owner of several rental properties, both in Tucson and in Washington, D.C., where he owned several hotels, including Arizona Hotel and The Patience (Rochester Hotel). Materials relating to the politics and governance of Tucson in the 1880’s are also present. Family materials, research/genealogical materials and photographs document several generations of the Sanford family. Correspondence between Don A. Sanford’s daughter Amo Sanford McKee, her daughter Louise McKee (Summers) and her future husband, Arizona writer Richard Aldrich Summers is also present. The photographs/negatives include various images of the Stock Valley Ranch and the Aztec/ 97 Ranch, as well as early photos of Tucson, San Xavier del Bac, Tumacácori and Altar, Mexico.
Sanford, Don Alonzo, 1840-1915; Sheep industry -- Arizona -- History -- Sources; Cattle trade -- Arizona -- History; Cattle brands -- Arizona; Cattle brands -- Texas; Frontier and pioneer life -- Arizona; Indians of North America—Texas; Kiowa Indians; Comanche Indians; Indians of North America -- Claims against; Land titles -- Arizona -- History -- Sources; Land grants -- Arizona; San Jose de Sonoita Land Grant (Ariz.); Ranches -- Arizona -- Records and correspondence; Patagonia (Ariz.)—History; Sonoita (Ariz.)—History; Tucson (Ariz.) – History; Cochise County (Ariz.) –History; Pima County (Ariz.) – History; Fort Huachuca (Ariz.) –History; Camp Crittenden (Ariz.) -- History; Washington (D.C.)—History; Summers, Richard, 1906-; Nation, Carry Amelia, 1846-1911
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1862-1967 (bulk 1870-1915)
  This series is divided into two subseries—business and personal correspondence. The material is arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent. Items within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries 1: Business >
    This subseries contains correspondence from business and professional associates.
    - A, 1885-1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, C.J., 1892 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - B, 1869-1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bayard, Jas. A., 1886 (acting Governor of Arizona) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bayes, Joe, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Burns, A.J., 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - C, 1883-1902 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Corbett, J. Knox, 1890-1903 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - D, 1884-1886 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - D, 1885-1893 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Demartini, P.A., 1889 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dickinson, William W, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - D, 1885-1893 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ertel, George, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - F, 1883-1912 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Forrest, C.M., 1900-1901 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Forrest, C.M., 1902-1904 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - G, 1881,1886 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - H, 1879-1897 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Hawley, Marcus C, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Holden, A.M., 1893 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Hughes, Josephine Brawley, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Hughes, L.C., 1888 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Hughes, Samuel, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - I, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Letters of recommendation for Don Sanford, 1878-1888 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - K, 1883,1890 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Kincaid, S.S, 1891-1899 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Latimer, Guy, 1910-1915 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - L, 1884, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - M, 1837-1895 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Maish, Levi, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Mason, Weltha, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - McKee, Fred, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - N, 1881, 1884, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - O, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - P, 1889, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - R, 1882,1885, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Rich, John S., 1881-1886 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Rouse, Owen T., 1893 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - S, 1879-1912 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo, 1884-1896 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Scott, William A., 1883 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Starkweather, John C., 1887, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Steinfeld, Albert, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Sykes, C.P., 1883-1890 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Sykes, Eugene and Mary, 1881-1891 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - U, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - W, 1888-1891 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Watkins, C.C., 1890 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Western Union Telegraph Company, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Williams, H.G., 1881 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 2: Personal>
    This subseries contains correspondence from various friends and family.
    - A, 1878-1900 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - B, 1878-1906 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Barnes, W.A., 1889-1890 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bloxton, A.E., 1903, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bloxton, B.B., 1878, 1890-1901 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Bloxton, Charles B., 1887-1901 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Bloxton, Colin, 1899-1901 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bloxton, Conway P., 1903 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bloxton, J.B., 1878-1895 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bloxton, James W., 1893-1896 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bloxton, Letitia, 1902-1903 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bloxton, Lizzie, 1897-1902 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Bloxton, R.H., 1881 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bloxton, Rebekah, 1876-1885, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Bloxton, Robert V. to Louisa Bloxton Sanford, 1889-1899 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Bloxton, Thomas, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Bloxton, William E., 1892-1898 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bloxton, William E., 1899-1903 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bond, Sarah, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Brissey, B.T., 1894-1896 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Burnes, Alta Sanford, 1906, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - C, 1905, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Cutler, M.H., 1893-1894 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - D, 1883-1898 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Davison, C.C., 1890 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Dravenstatt, Ida Sanford, 1889-1914 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - E, 1879-1900 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Elkins, Margaret, 1875-1879 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - England, Lizzie, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - F, 1902, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Fish, B.A., 1879-1896 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Fish, B.A., 1897-1904 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Fish, B.A., 1905-1915 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Forrest, C.M., 1897-1898 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - G, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - H, 1880-1896 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Haynes, Earl, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - J, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Jenison, W.F., 1890 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Johnson, Ralph, 1883-1894 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Johnson, Ralph, 1894-1913 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - K, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Kellogg, Charles, (Civil War Union 2 color stationary) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Latimer, Guy, 1914-1915 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - M, 1871-1925 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - McKee, Amita to Richard Summers, 1924-1926 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - McKee, Fred, 1903-1905, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Miller, Samuel, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - P, 1896-1898 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Packard, Arba, 1865-1902 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Parkhurst, W.D.A., 1881 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Patterson, Nina, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Poston, Charles D., 1884-1893 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - R, 1894-1915 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Rahl, Jennie, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - S, 1883-1908 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Sanford, Brook, 1864-1888 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Sanford, Catherine, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Sanford, Charlotte, 1869-1904 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Sanford, Denton G., 1865-1884 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo to Amo Sanford, 1886-1892 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo to Bertha Sanford, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo to Don A. Sanford, Jr., 1897-1906 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo to Etta Sanford, 1886-1887 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo to all his children, 1891-1909 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo to Louisa Bloxton Sanford, 1874-1896 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo to Louisa Bloxton Sanford, 1897-1912 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo to Mabel Sanford, 1891-1912 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo to Robert Bloxton, 1885-1897 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo, Jr., 1904-1914 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo, Jr., incoming—1900-1920 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Sanford, Don Alonzo, Jr. to Louisa Bloxton Sanford, 1899-1912 (Box 6, 9)
    - Sanford, Etta, 1883-1896 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Sanford, Etta, 1899-1911 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sanford, Franklin, 1870-1874 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Sanford, Greta, 1932-1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Sanford, Louisa Bloxton, 1875-1887 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Sanford, Louisa Bloxton, 1888-1891 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Sanford, Louisa Bloxton, 1892-1896 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sanford, Louisa Bloxton, 1897-1912 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Sanford, Louisa Bloxton to Don A. Sanford, Jr., 1899-1915 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sanford, Louisa Bloxton to her daughters, 1892-1917 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Sanford, Mary, 1885-1886 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Sanford, Narcissa (“Nart”), 1893-1909 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Sanford, Nell, 1869-1907 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sanford, Oscar, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sanford, Phyllis, 1929-1931, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Sanford, Tom, 1893-1910 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Sanford, William, transcribed, 1839 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Sanford Latimer, Mabel, 1882-1914 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Sanford Latimer, Mabel to Don Sanford, Jr., 1903-1904 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Sanford McKee, Amo, 1886-1896 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Sanford McKee, Amo, 1897-1911 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Sanford McKee, Amo and Richard Summers, 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Sanford McKee, Amo and Richard Summers, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Sanford McKee, Amo and Richard Summers, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, 1894-1912 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, 1910 (from Jackson Health Resort) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, 1917-1920 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, 1927-1967 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, postcards, 1906-1909 (Box 9, 7)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, postcards, 1910-1911 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, postcards, 1912-1913 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, postcards, 1914-1915 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, postcards, 1916-1917 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, postcards, 1918-1920 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha, postcards, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha to Don A. Sanford, Jr., 1903-1904 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Sanford Miller, Bertha to Greta Sanford, 1924-1931 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Sickner, A.W. and Julia, 1890-1909 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Simonson, C.S., 1891-1914 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Stuart, J.H., 1881, 1896 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Stuart, Irving J., 1887 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Summers, Louise McKee, 1946-1991 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Summers, Louise McKee and Richard Summers, 1924-1927 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Summers, Richard, 1924-1925, 1954-1957 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - T, 1881, 1884 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Thompson, Nell Tring, 1890-1909 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Transcribed letters—Sanford family, 1812-1870 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Transcribed letters—Sanford family, 1870-1877 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Transcribed letters—Sanford family, 1878-1927 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Tring, W.H., 1891-1915 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - V, 1879, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified, 1876-1887 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Van Voorhis, Angie, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - W, 1876-1913 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - White, E.S., 1893 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - White, Robinson, 1886 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 3: Letter Books 1886-1914>
    The books in this subseries contain copies of letters written by Don Alonzo Sanford to various correspondents, regarding both business-related and personal matters.
    - 1886-1867 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1889-1890 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1890-1894 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1899-1909 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 1894-1899 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1904-1909 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1909-1914 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1909-1910 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Series II: Diaries/Ledgers 1850-1919 (bulk 1880-1915)
  This series is comprised of Don A. Sanford’s large collection of diaries, financial ledgers, rental and miscellaneous account books. Also included are Sanford’s “Books of Knowledge”, large ledger books comprised of records of great detail and variety documenting many aspects of his life from 1850-1892. This series also contains the diaries and ledger accounts kept by Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, wife of Don Alonzo Sanford, which detail her transition from urban Washington, D.C. to life on their cattle and sheep ranch in the Arizona Territory near Patagonia in the mid 1870’s. This series also includes writings by Don Alonzo Sanford about various Tucson issues, conflicts between Native American peoples and U.S. settlers, and many detailed inventories, lists and accounts of varying types. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - 1859-1861 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1868-1873 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 1879-1881 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 1879-1881 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 1881-1882 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - November 1881-January 1882 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 1882 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - September-November 1882 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - November-December 1882 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - 1882-1883 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - 1882-1886 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 1882-1886 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - January-March 1883 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - March-April 1883 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - May-August 1883 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 1884 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 1885 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - 1885 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - 1886-1887 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 1887-1888 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - 1888 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 1889-1890 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 1889-1890 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - 1890-1891 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - 1891-1892 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - June 1891-February 1892 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - 1892-1893 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - May-August 1893 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - 1894-1895 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - 1894-1895 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - April-September 1895 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - June 1895 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - July 1895 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - August-September 1895 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - September-October 1895 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - October-November 1895 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - November-December 1895 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - January-April 1896 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - April-May 1896 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - July-October 1896 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - October 1896-February 1897 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 1896-1897 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 1897 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - February-April 1897 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 1887-1898 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - 1897-1919 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 1898 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - June-July 1898 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - September-November 1898 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - 1898 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - 1898-1899 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - April-July 1899 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - June-September 1899 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - July-September 1899 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - September-October 1899 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 1900 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - 1900-1909 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - January 1900-January 1901 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - March-April 1901 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - July-September 1901 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - January-June 1902 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - 1902-1903 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 1903 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 1903 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - 1904 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - 1904 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - 1904 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - 1904-1910 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - 1905 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - 1906 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1907 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 1907-1918 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - 1909 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - 1910 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - 1911-1912 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - October 1911-December 1912 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - 1912 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - October-November 1912 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - 1913 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - 1913-1915 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - 1914 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - 1915 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Index #1, circa 1901-1903 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Index #2, circa 1901-1903 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1875 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1876-1877 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1885-1888 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1878-1879 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1880 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1885-1886 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1887-1888 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1889 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1892 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1893-1896 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1896 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1899, 1912 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1899-1912 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1910-1915 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1910-1917 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1912 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1915-1917 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford, 1917-1919 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford—photocopies, 1875-1888 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Louisa Jane Bloxton Sanford—transcription of diaries, 1876-1890 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous unbound ledger pages, 1878-1916 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous unbound ledger pages, 1893-1914 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - 8 Miscellaneous unbound ledger pages, 1894-1917 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Oversize ledgers—“Book of Knowledge”, 1850-1897 (Box 27)
  - Oversize ledgers—“Book of Knowledge”, 1890-1892 (Box 28)
  - Oversize ledgers—miscellaneous accounts, 1904-1907 (Box 29)